Guide to the Adler hip hop archive, circa 1970-2013.
Adler hip hop archive
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Adler hip hop archive, circa 1970-2014.
8092
Adler, Bill,
36.5 cubic feet, 6 map-case folders and 46 framed items
Audio recordings, printed materials, publications, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Adler Archive includes letters, documents, manuscripts, images, magazine and newspaper articles, books, sound and video recordings, and other ephemera documenting the history of hip hop.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Bill Adler is an American music journalist and critic who specializes in hip hop. He was director of publicity at Def Jam Recordings between 1984 and 1990. Since the early 1980s he has promoted hip hop in a variety of capacities, including as publicist, biographer, record label executive, museum consultant, curator, and documentary filmmaker.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Adler Archive includes letters, documents, manuscripts, images, magazine and newspaper articles, books, sound and video recordings, and other ephemera documenting the history of hip hop. At the core of the Archive are files on more than 1400 hip hop artists and groups from the 1970s to the present. The files include press clippings, promotional head shots, record label press releases, promotional flyers and other ephemera.
The Adler Collection formed the basis for much of the illustrated content in the popular book Def Jam recordings: The first 25 years of the last great record label (2011).
SUBJECTS
Names:
Adler, Bill, 1951- ,; Def Jam Recordings.
Subjects:
Hip-hop -- United States.; Sound recording industry -- United States.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Restrictions on Access:
Box 45 is restricted until 2050
Collection may be used one folder at a time.
SERIES LIST
Series I. News Files
Boxes 1-28; Box 45
Box 45 is RESTRICTED until 2050
News Files 1980s
Performer Names A-H
Performer Names I-P
Performer Names Q-Z
News Files 1990s and 2000s
Performer Names A-H
Performer Names I-P
Performer Names Q-Z
Series II. Posters and Framed Items
Box 29, Mapcases
Series III. Records and Other Media
Boxes 30-44
Separated Material
Includes books catalogued individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript collections.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. News Files
  - News Files 1980s
    - Performer Names A-H
      - Afrocentrism, 1989-93 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - The Aleems, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Harry Allen, 1991-2002, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Antoinette, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Arabian Prince, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Carmen Ashhurst, 1992, 2002-2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Atlantis Productions (Rolando Hudson and Pam Gibson), c. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Audio 2, 1988-1994, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Awesome 2, 1990-1996, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Arthur Baker, 1983-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Afrika Bambaataa/Zulu Nation
        - A. Bambaataa discography, No Date (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - A. Bambaataa/Zulu Nation flyers and photos, 1984-2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - A. Bambaataa feature in Wax Poetics magazine, No Date; CD-2083 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - A. Bambaataa bios, 1992, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - A. Bambaataa '80s, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - A. Bambaataa '90s, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - Zulu anniversaries, 1992-1997, 2004-2010 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Copies of the Zulu News, c. 1992-1994, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - Zulu Nation press releases, 1993-1998, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - News coverage of the Bronx River Houses versus the Zulu Nation, 1995, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - A. Bambaataa and associates 2000s, 2000-2013 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Dee Barnes, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Rob Base and DJ E-Z Rock, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Basehead, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Beastie Boys
        - Beastie Boys photos, c. 1985-1998 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Beastie Boys docs, scanned October, 2013, October 2013; CD-2084 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        - Beastie Boys on tour with Madonna '85, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        - Beastie Boys '85, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - Beastie Boys '86, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        - Beastie Boys '87, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        - Beastie Boys "Licensed to Ill" tour press, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
          Beastie Boys LIC to ILL tour booklet
        - Beastie Boys non-U.K. foreign press, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        - Beastie Boys U.K. Press, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
        - Beastie Boys press from the files of Noah Uman, unsourced, '85-'87, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
        - Beastie Boys bio material '87, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
        - Beastie Boys sue Budweiser, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
        - Beastie Boys '88, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 35)
        - Beastie Boys '89, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 36)
        - Beastie Boys '92, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
        - Beastie Boys '93, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 38)
        - Beastie Boys '94, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 39)
        - Beastie Boys '95, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 40)
        - Beastie Boys '96, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 41)
        - Beastie Boys '97, 1997 (2011) (Box 1, Folder 42)
        - Beastie Boys '98-'99, 1998-1999 (2001) (Box 1, Folder 43)
        - Beastie Boys '00-'01, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 44)
        - Beastie Boys '02, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 45)
        - Beastie Boys '03-'04, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 46)
        - Beastie Boys '05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 47)
        - Beastie Boys '06-'10, 2006-2010 (Box 1, Folder 48)
        - Beastie Boys '11, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 49)
        - Beastie Boys '12, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 50)
        - Adam Yauch dies, May 2012, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 51)
        - Beastie Boys '13, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 52)
        - Adam Horovitz '13, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - "Beat Street" (movie), 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - "Big Fun in Big Town" (movie), 1986, 2012; DVD-1072 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        Early Dutch documentary about rap scene in New York. Includes DVD of the film.
      - Biz Markie, 1988-2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Black, Rock and Ron, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Black Flames, 1987, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Kurtis Blow
        - Kurtis Blow photos, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
          Includes Slides
        - Kurtis Blow bios, c. 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Kurtis Blow '80-'83, 1980-1983 (2010) (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - Kurtis Blow '84, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Kurtis Blow '85, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Kurtis Blow '86-'88, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Kurtis Blow '90s, 1990-1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - Kurtis Blow - We Care About New York, Inc, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
          Kurtis Blow involved with social program called We Care About New York
        - Kurtis Blow regarding "The Breaks" documentary, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Kurtis Blow '00-'13, 2000-2013 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Boogie Boys, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Boogie Down Productions (a/k/a BDP), 1987-1992, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Duke Bootee, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Sophie Bramly, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Brand Nubian, 1989-2005 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Breakdancing, 1982-1985, 1998-2008 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - "Breakin" (movie), 1984, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - MC Breed, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Breeze, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Darryl Brooks/Carol Kirkendall/ G Street Productions, No Date (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Alonzo Brown, proposal for a book about Harlem World nightclub, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Fred Buggs, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Busy Bee, 1987-2012 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Canadian Hip-Hop, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Captain Rock photos, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Sean Carasov, 2005-2012 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        RESTRICTED until 2050 - Moved to Box 45, Folder 1
      - Cash Money and Marvelous, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - C-Funk, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Dan Charnas
        - Dan Charnas, 2001-2008 (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - Dan Charnas, press materials about "The Big Payback", 2007-2011 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - Dan Charnas, draft of chapter about Def Jam for "The Big Payback," summer '09, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 36)
          Includes edits by Bill Adler
      - Eddie Cheba, 2000, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        Includes copies of fliers from 1978
      - Chill Rob G, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Chuck Chillout, 1989-1992, 2000-2012 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Brian Chin, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Chubb Rock, 1989-1997 (2006) (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Chuck D
        - "Autobiography of Mistachuck" (solo album), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - Transcript of Chuck D interview by Bill Adler for Perry Films’s “And You Don’t Stop” documentary, July 14, 2003., 2003 (Box 2, Folder 43)
        - Chuck D '90s, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 44)
        - Chuck D '00-'09, 2000-2009 (Box 2, Folder 45)
        - Chuck D '10-'12, 2010-2012 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Chung King (recording studio), 2008-2012 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Rodger Clayton/Uncle Jamm's Army, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Lyor Cohen
        - Lyor Cohen photos, 1985-1989, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 49)
        - Prints and damaged negatives of photos of Lyor by Ricky Powell, No Date (Box 2, Folder 50)
        - Lyor '87-'03, 1987-2003 (Box 2, Folder 51)
        - Lyor '04-'12, 2004-2012 (Box 2, Folder 52)
        - Lyor and colleagues at the Apollo Theater, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 53)
        - TVT sues Def Jam: transcript of Lyor’s testimony, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 54)
          RESTRICTED until 2050 - Moved to Box 45, Folder 2
        - Lyor '13, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Cold Chillin' Records, 1991-2005 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Cold Crush Brothers, 1983-2010 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Cookie Crew, 1989, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Lisa Cortes, 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - Crack rap, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Crash Crew, 2002-2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Frankie Crocker, 1977-2000, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Daddy-O, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Dana Dane, 1985-1995, 2007-2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Danceteria (nightclub), 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Dapper Dan, 2012-2013 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        Includes copies of material from the 1980s
      - Dasez Tempo, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Davy D a/k/a/ Davy DMX (born David Reeves Jr.)
        - Davy D, 1984-1988, 2007-2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - Davy D, Redman 12-inch covers, No Date; CD-2085 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - De La Soul
        - De la Soul photos, 2000-2001, No Date (Box 3, Folder 10)
        - De la Soul '89, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - De la Soul '90, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - De la Soul '91-'92, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
        - De la Soul '93-'94, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - De la Soul '96, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - De la Soul '00-'02, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - De la Soul '06-'11, 2006-2011 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Delicious Vinyl (record label), 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Derek B, 1988-2009 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Diamond D, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Digital Underground
        - Digital Underground U.K. press, 1989-990 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - Digital Underground, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        - Digital Underground press campaign, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Disco Fever (nightclub), 1983-1986, 2001-2005 (Box 3, Folder 24)
        Includes a treatment of the movie "The Fever"
      - Disco Wiz, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy photos, c. 1992 (Box 3, Folder 26)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy: transcript of interview of Michael Franti by Ishmael Reed, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        - Franti/Reed, No Date; 4.5 inch FD-9 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy '91-'92, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy - label business '91, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy '92, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 30)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy - memos, etc. '92, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 31)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy '93, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 32)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy, monthly press reports, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy lyrics, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy U.K. and foreign press, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 35)
        - Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy on tour with U2, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 36)
        - Photos of Disposable Heroes of HipHoprisy with Tony Bennett, No Date (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Divine Sounds, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - DJ A.J., a/k/a AJ and AJ Scratch
        - A.J. letters from prison '98-'99, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 39)
          RESTRICTED until 2050 - Moved to Box 45, Folder 3
        - A.J. Comic Strip, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 40)
        - A.J. money transfers '03-'04, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 41)
        - A.J. '00-'13, 2000-2013 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - DJ Doc, 1990, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - DJ Eddie F., 1990-1991, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - DJ Hollywood, 2004-2008 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - DJ Joe, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - DJ Mark, the 45 King, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - The D.O.C., 1989-1991, 2001-2007 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Double Dee and Steinski, 1986, 2003-2013 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Peter Dougherty, 2006-2012 (Box 3, Folder 50)
        Includes copies of materials from the 1980s
      - Doctor Dre and Ed Lover, 1990-2012 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Ed Lover flyers, ads, 1992-2012 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Dream Warriors
        - Dream Warriors '91-'92, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 53)
        - Dream Warriors photos, flyers, ads, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 54)
        - Dream Warriors press releases, etc., 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 55)
        - Dream Warriors press copies, 1991 (1999) (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Dream Warriors '95, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Dynasty and Mimi, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Egyptian Lover, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - EPMD
        - EPMD photos, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - EPMD '88-'89, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - EPMD '90-2012, 1990-2012 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - EPMD - U.K. press, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Eric B. and Rakim
        - Eric B and Rakim photos, 1987-1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Rakim photos and Wax Poetics Rakim Scans, 2005, 2012; CD-2086-2087 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Eric B and Rakim '87, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Eric B and Rakim '88, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        - Eric B and Rakim '89, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Eric B and Rakim '90-'91, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        - Eric B and Rakim '92-'11, 1992-2011 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Fab 5 Freddy, 1989-1993, 2001-2011 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - The Fat Boys, 1984-1997, 2006-2013; CD-2088 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Fearless Four, 1983-1984, 1997, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Kate Ferguson, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Skiz Fernando, 2008-2012 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Fire This Time "Dancing on John Waynes Head", 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Force MD's, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Robert "Rocky" Ford, 1987, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Doug E. Fresh
        - Doug E. Fresh photos, 1987-1995, No Date (Box 4, Folder 23)
        - Doug E. Fresh '80s, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
        - Doug E. Fresh '90-'02, 1990-2002 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        - Doug E. Fresh press copies, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        - Doug E. Fresh '00-'13, 2000-2013 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Full Force, 1984-2001 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Funky 4 plus 1, 1980-1981, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Gangsta Rap debate, 1987-1995, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Gangsta Rap debate, 1990-1996; 3.5 inch FD-10 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Gangsta Rap debate, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Gang Starr
        - Gang Starr photos, 1992-1997, No Date (Box 4, Folder 33)
        - Gang Starr lyrics, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        - Gang Starr press copies '90s, 1991-1999 (Box 4, Folder 35)
        - Gang Starr '90s, 1991-1999 (Box 4, Folder 36)
        - Gang Starr '02-'13, 2002-2013 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Antoine Garnier, 1999-2009 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - Antoine Garnier photos, 1994, No Date (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - Nelson George, 1986-2005 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Ghettorigionals, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Michael Gonzales, (1992) 1999-2006 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Tipper Gore, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Grandmaster Flash and the Furious Five, 1983-2013 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Grandmaster Flash - Queens Armory, Early 1980s; CD-2089 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Grandmixer DST, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Grand Wizard Theodore, 1999-2007 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Greene Street Recording, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Professor Griff, 1989-2011 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Groove Garden, No Date (Box 4, Folder 49)
      - Guru and "Jazzmatazz"
        - Guru and "Jazzmatazz" '92-'93, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Jazzmatazz 2 '95, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        - Guru, "Jazzmatazz Streetsoul," '00, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        - Guru dies, April 10, 2010, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Hambo, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - MC Hammer, 1989-1995, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Dream Hampton, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Andre Harrell, 1985-2012; CD-2090 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Heavy D
        - Heavy D, 1987-2011 (Box 5, Folder 9)
        - Heavy D photos, 1986-1999 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - "Hip Hop Family Tree" (comic book)
        - "Hip Hop Family Tree" comic, 2012-2013 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - "Hip Hop Family Tree", 2012 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Hip hop hair, 1999-2010 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - "Hip Hop Hit List" (magazine), 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - "Hip Hop Immortals" (book), 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Hip Hop and Islam, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Hip Hop Summit, June 2001, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Hollis Crew, No Date (Box 5, Folder 18)
        (Empty)
      - Michael Holman
        - Michael Holman, 1992, 2006-2013 (Box 5, Folder 19)
        - Michael Holman screenplay '03, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Cynthia Horner, 1988, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Hot 97 (New York radio station), 1995, 2005-2008 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - H-Town, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Performer Names I-P
      - Ice-T
        - Ice-T until '92, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 24)
        - Ice-T '92, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 25)
        - Ice-T '93, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 26)
        - Ice-T -'94-'00, 1994-2000 (Box 5, Folder 27)
        - Ice-T '01-'10, 2001-2010 (Box 5, Folder 28)
        - Ice- T '11-'13, 2011-2013 (Box 5, Folder 29)
        - "The Art of Rap" (documentary film), 2012 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - George Jackson and Doug McHenry, 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Jesse Jackson, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Jazzy Jay, (1985,) 2003-2010 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince photos, 1987-1990; CD-2091 (Box 5, Folder 34)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince '87, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 35)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince '88, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 36)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince copies of press clips '88, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 37)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince '89, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 38)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince Grammy Awards boycott, Feb.'89, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 39)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince copies of press clips '88, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 40)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince copies of press clips '89, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 41)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince '90, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        - Jazzy Jeff and the Fresh Prince '91-'08, 1991-2008 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Jazzy Joyce, 1986, 2004-2013 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Dr. Jeckyll and Mr. Hyde, 1984-2010 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Jive/Zomba Records, 1995-2008 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - JJ Fad, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Joeski Love, 1986-1990 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Oran "Juice" Jones
        - Oran "Juice" Jones photos, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 49)
        - Oran "Juice" Jones '86, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 50)
        - Oran "Juice" Jones '87, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 51)
        - "Soul Songs" - Tour of Europe, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Oran "Juice" Jones '88-'89, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - Oran "Juice" Jones '12, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Jungle Brothers
        - Jungle Brothers, 1989-2003 (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - Jungle Bros U.K. press, 1988-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Junkyard Band, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Just-Ice, 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Ini Kamoze, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Big Daddy Kane
        - Big Daddy Kane, 1988-2013 (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - Big Daddy Kane, bios, press releases, etc, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Big Daddy Kane photos, 1988-2011 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - Kangols, 1988-1995 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - KDAY (L.A. radio station), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Kid'n'Play and "House Party" (movie), 1988-1992, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Kid Frost, 1990-1995 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Kid Rock, 1993-2012 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Martin Luther King, "King Holiday" benefit record, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - King Sun, 1989-1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Dave "Funken" Klein, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Kool G Rap and D.J. Polo, 1992-2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Kool Herc, 2000-2013 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Kool Moe D, 1984-1994, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - KRS-One
        - KRS-One photos, 1993-2002 (Box 6, Folder 23)
        - Transition - interview w/ KRS-One, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 24)
        - KRS-One '80s, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 25)
        - KRS-One '90s, 1990-1999 (Box 6, Folder 26)
        - KRS-One 2000-2013, 2000-2013 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - "Krush Groove" (movie)
        - "Krush Groove" contact sheets for location shots by Chase Roe, c. 1985 (Box 6, Folder 28)
        - "Krush Groove", 1985-1986, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - K-Solo, 1990, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Lady B, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Laquan, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - L.A. Star, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Queen Latifah
        - Queen Latifah '80s-'90s, 1989-1999 (Box 6, Folder 34)
        - Queen Latifah '00-'09, 2000-2009 (Box 6, Folder 35)
        - Queen Latifah '10-'12, 2010-2012 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Latin Quarter (nightclub), 2007 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Latin Rascals, 1985, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Spike Lee, 1987-1995, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Cara Lewis, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - Alan Light, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - Lionel D (French rapper), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 42)
      - Live Squad interview and press materials, c. 1992 (Box 6, Folder 43)
      - LL Cool J
        - LL Cool J photos, c. 1985-1995 (Box 6, Folder 44)
        - LL Cool J '84-'85, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 45)
        - LL Cool J '86, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 46)
        - LL Cool J photos, c. 1987 (Box 6, Folder 47)
        - LL Cool J foreign press, 1986-1992 (Box 6, Folder 48)
        - LL Cool J, Rush-Def Jam tour '87, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        - LL Cool J tour book '87, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - LL Cool J '87 ('88), 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - LL Cool J U.K. press, 1985-1988 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - LL Cool J '88, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - LL Cool J business documents '89, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
          RESTRICTED until 2050 - Moved to Box 45, Folder 4
        - LL Cool J '89, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)